If you are a credentialed non-arts teacher
and you want to teach the arts,
One pathway is to add a supplementary authorization
to your existing credential.
For mutiple subject credential holders,
adding a supplementary authorization
allows you to teach the arts
in grade nine and below.
You'll need 20 semester units,
or 10 upper division semester units
in the content area.
For example,
a dance authorization
must include classes
from the dance department,
and only units from
institutions of higher education are allowed.
The advantage is,
you don't need any classes or exams,
and the application is made directly to the CTC.
For single-subject credential holders,
you can follow the same process
to add a specific supplementary authorization
Or if you choose, you can add
a second single subject
credential
by demonstrating subject matter competency
and taking a one-semester methods course
in an approved teacher
education program.
You can prove subject matter
competency
through a degree in dance, music, theatre,
or visual arts,
by taking the CSET,
or through a combination of college coursework
and one CSET.
So how do you begin?
Review your transcripts
and consult the CTC website
for specific information
regarding supplementary authorizations.
Because individual
circumstances can vary
and there are some limitations
on what subjects can be taught,
we recommend reviewing the CTC guidance
and contacting the Commission directly
with specific questions.
In general though, the process
is more straightforward
than you might think.